If you are looking for the best health insurance plan for yourself
and are confused whether to
buy IIC Lord's Elevate plan or NB's
Aspire, then this video is going to be very important for you.
In this video, we will provide a
detailed comparison of both the plans,
analyze their features and benefits,
look at their pros and cons, and
analyze the premium. At the
end of the video, I
will analyze the claim settlement and, based on all these parameters,
we will also try to find out
which plan is best for you.
So, watch this video completely till the end. Do
not skip any part. Hello
friends, I am Ashutosh, your personal
finance coach. Let's start the video.
Let's first discuss the basic features of the plan.
Talking about the minimum and maximum age, the minimum age for Niva Bupa Aspire is
18 years and the maximum
entry age is 65 years and
90 days for newborn babies. Whereas, there is no maximum entry age for IIC Lamba Daily Veterinary Plan.
You can enroll in this plan at any age.  You can enter,
so senior citizens after the age of
65 can also enter this plan. Sum
assured option is available in Niva Bupa Aspire from Rs 3 lakh to Rs 1
crore, whereas
sum assured options of Rs 5 lakh to Rs 3 crore
are available in IIC Lamba Elevate and along with that, we
also have an unlimited sum assured option available.
Meaning, if you feel that even Rs 3 crore
is not sufficient, then you
can select the unlimited option in which the
sum insured will not be counted.
Room category: There is no room category wise capping in Niva Bupa Aspire, you
can take a room of any category. There is a capping for
single private AC room in Lord Elevate,
but along with that, you can avail room
modification
treatment, alternate treatment, Ayurvedic,
Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy, all treatments
up to sum assured are covered in both the plans
for pre and post hospitalization.
Pre
hospitalization 60 days and post in Niva Bupa Aspire  There is a cover of 180 days,
whereas in ICICI Lord Elevate,
pre-hospitalization is covered for 90 days and post-
hospitalization is covered for 180 days. Our
health insurance covers hospitalization of more than 24 hours,
but there are
many treatments or surgeries or
procedures in which inpatient
treatment is done but the duration of
hospitalization is not of 24 hours.
We get discharged within a procedure of a few hours only. Such treatments
come under the category of day care treatment
and all day care treatments
are covered in both the plants. Organ donor cover
is available up to the
sum in Niva Bupa Spar. You have another
additional benefit in Niva Bupa Spar. If the donor also has a
Niva Bupa Aspire policy, then the
transplant charges will also be covered in his policy.
Domicile
Hospitalization:
If we take home hospitalization in any emergency condition, then it
comes under the category of domicile hospitalization. Up to the sum is covered in both the plants.
Home care treatments are such
treatments in which
we can take those treatments at home after consulting a doctor,
such as some physiotherapy,
chemotherapy, dialysis, we can take these types of treatments at
home, which
are covered up to the sum assured in Niva Bupa Aspire, but not in ICICI Elevate,
but we get a Nursing at Home
rider which covers the
nursing charges at home in post hospitalization.
Road Ambulance is covered up
to the sum assured in both the plans.
Air Ambulance is covered
up to the sum assured in both the plans.
Air Ambulance is inbuilt cover in Niva Bupa Aspire,
whereas in ICICI Elevate we have to buy As an add-on.
Free Health Checkup:
Free Health Checkup is available in Niva Bupa Aspire,
whereas in ICICI Elevate
we have to purchase As a rider. Free
Health Checkup: Modern Treatment: Up
to the sum assured
is covered in both the plans. Second Medical Opinion:
Unlimited times Second Medical Opinion in Niva Aspire  It is
available, whereas there is
no second medical opinion in ICICI Lord Elevate.
E-consultation
is available unlimited times inbuilt in Niva BPA Aspire, whereas
it is available as an add-on in ICICI Elevate.
Talking about maternity coverage,
we get maternity coverage in both the plans. Niva
BPA Aspire has inbuilt
maternity cover, which means that we do not have to pay
any extra payment or extra
premium for this coverage. The
waiting period for maternity is
different in different variants.
48 months for Gold variant, 24 months for Diamond variant,
9 months for Platinum and Titan variants. The waiting period of
maternity will be applicable. The coverage of maternity also
depends on your sum insured.
You get different benefits for different sum insured.
For 3 lakh sum insured, Rs. 4000, for 5 lakh Rs.
5000, 7.5 lakh Rs. 10000, 10 lakh  For 12000,
15000, 20 lakh, 25 lakh, 2000000, and 50 lakh
and 25 year policies, you
get maternity benefits of Rs 25000 per year
for delivery and it can be accumulated up to 10 times.
Whereas
in ICICI Lord Elevate, you do
not get inbuilt maternity cover. You have to
take a separate rider for which you have to
pay a separate premium and its
benefit is Rs 10 per sum insured
maximum up to Rs 1 lakh, which means that it will be
available to you only up to a maximum of Rs 1 lakh.
Talking about newborn baby cover for delivery, the
most unique benefit of NP Air is
that the newborn baby cover in it is now twice the
sum insured, so if there is
any complication after delivery, then you
can manage it well with this policy.
Whereas in ICICI Lord Elevate, the
newborn baby cover is twice the
maternity cover.  This means that the
cover for your newborn baby will be
available only up to a maximum of Rs 2 lakh. Worldwide cover is
available as a rider in Niva, B, Aspire.
Worldwide cover option is not available in Borderless, III, Lord, Elevate.
Friends, as important as it is to purchase health
insurance, it is equally important to purchase it from the right source.
Health insurance is a very
long-term commitment and we have to
renew it for many years. Therefore, try to
purchase that policy after consulting a good financial advisor. There are many
online aggregator platforms where
you can find call centers and
those telecallers have
very
minimal knowledge of the health insurance industry. In such a situation, when you
face any issue at the time of claim, they are
unable to help you and you have to face trouble. So, do
not get caught in the trap of a discount of Rs 45 on the first year premium.
Consult a good advisor
and purchase a proper policy so that
your advisor can take care of the claim.  If there is any
issue, I
can help you with my experience and knowledge and
try to resolve that issue. Friends,
if you want to purchase or discuss your health insurance with me, then I
provide support on the number given below.
Talking about waiting periods,
both the plans have a 30-day initial waiting
period. A two-year waiting period for
specific diseases or a three-year pre-existing waiting period will be applicable for slow-growing
diseases and pre-existing conditions.
Both the plans are
very unique and have many such
features which are industry first and are
not seen anywhere else. First of all,
we discuss the unique features of N Bappa Insurance.
So the first unique feature is Lock
the Clock. This is a benefit which is
not seen anywhere else. Usually,
in every insurance plan,
our premium increases with our age band.
Generally, our premium increases in the age bracket of 5 years.  There is an
increase but
in np aspire till we do not make our first claim,
our premium remains
locked and does not increase. The
next important benefit is the booster
plus benefit in which our
unutilized sum insured gets carried forward
and it can be
carried forward maximum up to 10 times
and this booster plus benefit depends on the
inception date in our policy, it
depends on our inception age,
so if our age at the time of policy inception is
less than 35 then the booster plus
benefit will be available up to 10 times, if it is 35 to 45 then it will be
five times and if it is above 45 then it will be
available maximum three times only. The next
important benefit is
rearranging restore which is available for full, partial,
related and unrelated illness as well. The
best benefit is
that after the second claim it is available for life time.
What is available in most of the plans?  It happens that every year, after the second claim,
we get the restore benefit available.
In Niva P Aspire, the
restore benefit after the second claim is
available for life time. Apart from this,
we get to see a disease management rider,
DM rider, which
covers hypertension and diabetes from day one without any
waiting period. Talking about the unique features of IIC Lord Elevate, the
first one is
Power Boost, in which we get 100%
cumulative bonus every year for life time. If
our policy is of Rs 10 lakh, then the
cumulative bonus of Rs 10 lakh will be received every year
and as long as we keep renewing,
we will keep getting it every year. This is a very
unique and industry first benefit.
Apart from this, we
can claim for an indefinite unlimited amount. So,
if we have a policy of Rs 5 or 10 lakh and we have cumulative bonus of Rs 10 or 20 lakh,
but a claim of Rs 80, 90 lakh or 1 crore has come, then
in such a situation, we  Claims can be
exercised through this rider. In this plan
also, we get the benefit of unlimited restore
for both full and partial. The
restore benefit with this plan has
a small capping that
for unrelated illnesses, it
is available for unlimited time. Unlimited time is also available for related illnesses
but there is a
cooling period of 45 days for that. So, related
illness means that if you have been
hospitalized once for a disease
and there is a second hospitalization for the same disease in the same year, then it will be a
related illness
and if you want to use the restore benefit for that, then it will be
available only after 45 days.
If we need the restore benefit before 45 days, then
it will not be available. Apart from this,
we get to see a Jump Start add-on in this
which covers hypertension, diabetes,
hyperlipidemia and obesity from day one
without any waiting period.
In both the plans, we get some  Optional
benefits are available in Niva Papa
Fair. The first is
Fast Forward, in which you can pay three years'
premiums in one go and receive all three years'
benefits at once. Those who are
single or married can avail this
rider to serve the maternity waiting period
themselves. In such a situation,
after marriage, they will not have to serve a separate maternity
waiting period.
Next is Cash Back, in which we get some cash
back which we can use for purchasing medicines,
diagnostic tests, deductible,
consultation etc. The next
benefit is Safeguard Plus, which is
for covering consumables. There are
many non-payable items which are
not covered in our policy.
To cover them, Safeguard Plus
rider also increases our basic sum assured against
inflation.
Next is Well Consult, which is an OPD
rider. If you need OPD with your policy,
you can take this rider.
Personal Accident Cover is
a fixed benefit rider that
provides a lump sum benefit in case of accidental death or disability. Next is
Hospital Cash, which provides cash benefits during hospitalization for out-of-pocket
expenses.
Next is
Deductible. This plan
also offers a deductible option. If you feel
that your premium is too high,
you can reduce your premium liability by opting for a deductible amount.
Talking about the optional covers of ICICI Lord Elevate, the
first is
Infidel Life Time, which gives you the
option to claim an unlimited sum insured.
Next is Inflation Protector, which increases the
basic sum assured against inflation.
Next
is the important Power Booster, which provides
1x coverage or 100% cumulative
bonus every year. Apart from this, Domestic Air
Ambulance Jump Start, which covers hypertension,
diabetes, hyperlipidemia, obesity without any cost.  The
waiting period covers
dependent accommodation, in which
we get some cash benefits for the accommodation of the dependent at the time of hospitalization.
Claim Protector: This rider is also there to
cover non-payable consumables.
This is an important rider which
we should take with our policy. The
next important rider is room modification,
with which we get the option of upgrade and downgrade.
With upgrade, we
can take any room of any category
and when we downgrade, we
get two options - twin sharing or
1 per sum assured limit. If we had
taken the downgrade option, we would have got
some discount in our policy, but
this is still not advisable. We should
take the upgrade option and not the downgrade.
Compassionate visit: If there is
hospitalization, then for visiting any immediate
family member, you
get the benefit of economy class air ticket for air fare. Nursing at home:
This is a post hospitalization benefit in
which you get up to Rs.
Services of a qualified nurse are available for up to 10 days and
her charges will be payable. Also, a maternity plan
is provided which includes the charges for maternity,
newborn baby and vaccination.
Next,
durable equipment:
If we require durable equipment like
pacemaker, oxygen cylinder, wheel chair etc. during hospitalization,
charges up to Rs 5 lakh will be available for it.
Cores benefit: If the hospitalization is
more than 10 days, then we get a one-time cash
benefit. Health checkup is an add-on.
We do not get an inbuilt health checkup.
Apart from this, we get a B-feed rider for OPD cover. The
next optional
benefit is Network Advantage, in which we get a
discount of 10% on our premium.
But we have to get our treatment done
in the list of preferred hospitals of ICICI Loyd. If
we get treatment done outside that, then a
payment of Rs 20% is applicable. So this is the
rider.  It's not advisable at all.
Furthermore, a personal accident and critical
illness rider is available. If you
want a fixed benefit policy
for personal accident and critical illness,
you can take this rider.
People often get confused about critical illness, as
this plan requires a separate policy to cover critical illness.
Friends, this critical illness rider
is for fixed benefit. Your policy
covers any disease, whether
critical or non-critical, but it
won't provide any cash benefit. The
critical illness rider is
for income replacement. If you're
not earning during a critical illness,
you can replace
your income with the cash benefit you receive from this rider. There's
also a
teleconsultation option to reduce the maternity
waiting period. There's an inbuilt two-year waiting
period for maternity, which you
can reduce to one year.
Apart from this, we also get the option of voluntary copayment.
If you feel
that your premium is getting high in higher age groups, then
you can reduce your premium by taking voluntary copayment.
For which
copayment options ranging from 10% to 50% are available.
In both the plans, we get to see people-wise
premium, but there is
no zone-wise copayment.
Talking about the premium, I have
taken the example of a 30-year-old couple with two
kits for daily NCR 10 lakh sum assured, in
which Aspire with Safeguard Plus
variant and AAA Elevate with Power
Booster and Fit Care Room are
modified.
Talking about the claim experience, friends,
I will not discuss the claim settlement at all. There
is a very misleading ratio,
seeing that we should not purchase any policy.
Talking about these card claim ratios, N
B Aspire has
65.4 and AAA Lombard has 72.6.  Whereas the
overall complaint ratio is 49 in Nip Aspire
and 13 in IIC Lord. You
can see that the complaint ratio is very low in IIII
and if we talk about after sales complaint ratio, it is
at 01 in both the plans
and premium wise both the plans are value
for money, their features are very good.
Friends, in this video we have analyzed all the features,
benefits and their pros and cons.
You can select
any of the two plans according to your need.
Still, if you are
confused about which plan you should take, then you
can connect on the number given below. Friends, if
you have any doubt related to this video, then do
ask by commenting below. If you liked this video, then do like
it and
subscribe to the channel so that
you keep getting such information videos.
Friends, that's all in today's video. See you
in the next video. Thank you.